Guide to the Mark Miller and Benmarl Winery Collection
Miller, Mark and Benmarl Winery Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mark Miller and Benmarl Winery Collection [bulk] 1970-1990.
6716
Mark, Miller 1919-
4.3 cubic ft.
Audio Recordings, Correspondence, Newspapers Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications, Video
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection includes information about Benmarl and Mark Miller.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Benmarl uses the slogan America's Oldest Vineyard. The winery is located in the Hudson Valley. Mark Miller and family took over the estate in 1957 naming it Benmarl. Ben is Gaelic for hill and marl describes soil. Miller helped lobby to pass winery legislation in New York. Benmarl holds N.Y. State Farm Winery Act license #1. Miller is also a noted wardrobe designer, illustrator and author.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection includes information about Benmarl, press kits, publication clippings, photographs other ephemera. Drafts of Mark Miller's book For the Love of Wine. Speeches given by Mark Miller about the wine industry and legislation. Videos and audio tapes regarding the winery. Information on the Benmarl Societe des Vignerons. Also some artwork by Miller. Farm Winery License FW1 and the pen used by Governor Hugh Carey to sign the act.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Miller, Mark,1919-; Miller, Mark, 1919-
Subjects:
Grape industry.; Grape industry--New York (State).; Grape industry--New York (State)--Hudson Valley Region.; Illustrations; License system.; Liquor industry.; Liquor laws.; Viticulture.; Viticulture--New York (State).; Wine bottles.; Wine--Marketing.; Wine industry--New York (State); Wine industry--New York (State); Wine industry--New York (State)--Hudson Valley Region.; Wine and wine making.; Wine and wine making--Hudson River Valley (N.Y. and N.J.); Wine and wine making--New York (State).; Wine and wine making--United States.
Places:
Marlboro (N.Y.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
A proof and first edition copy of Mark Miller's book, Wine a Gentleman's Game, the adventures of an amateur winemaker turned professional, are available in Rare call number TP557 .M64 1984.
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
SERIES LIST
Series I. General
Boxes: 1, 2, 4
Series II. Photographs
Box 2
Series III. Magazines
Box 2
Series IV. Newspaper Articles and other Publications
Boxes 2, 5
Series V. Audio and Video
Box 3
Series VI. Posters, Publication materials, Miller Art work and Drawings
Box 4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. General
  - Outline proposal for preservation of the Benmarl Winery in the Hudson Viewshed, Town of Marlborough, NY (3 copies), February 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron, Winter/Spring 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    The Official Wineletter of the Benmarl Societe des Vignerons
  - Valuation papers of property of Benmarl Vineyards, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Includes Real estate tax papers, sales papers, harvest production details
  - Appraisal of Benmarl Vineyards property - Pomeroy Appraisal Associates Inc, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Includes financial statements of Benmarl Vineyards 1988
  - The Gentleman's Game: The Story of Benmarl Vineyards (2 copies) (Mark Miller), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Proposals Reviewed by Benmarl Vineyards, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Includes Pomeroy appraisal, full equipment listings, financials for 1991 and 1992
  - Miscellanous materials 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Includes vineyard tour details, balance sheets, expense reports, analysis reports
  - Miscellanous materials 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proposals for future of Benmarl (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Summary Description of Benmarl for Employees (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Benmarl Vineyards Bond series, Investment details, Society Structure (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Includes Mark Miller's resumes
  - Family History (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Financial Management for Beer Wholesalers (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Speeches - Mark Miller (A) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Horticultural Heyday, April 1978
    - General Winemaking, April 1978
    - Premium Eastern Wines for Early Consumption, July 1978
    - Vinification Methods With The Direct Producers, November 1977
    - Wine is a Complement to Food, February 1977
    - Small Business Can Affect Legislation, February 1999
    - Speech for Vassar Hospital Women's Group, March 1976
    - Speech for the New Paltz Businessmen's Dinner, October 1976
    - Speech for Ladies Club, Wappinger Falls, October 1977
    - Testimony on Public Hearing At Farm And Food Policy, January 1976
    - Miscellanous Speeches
  - Speeches - Mark Miller (B) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Senior Citizens
    - Wine is one of our oldest and simplest foods
    - The Value of Wine As A Food (Maynard Amerine)
    - Wineries Unlimited Seminar
    - Viticulture in the Hudson Valley
    - The Tasting Tools You Have To Work With
    - Speech to Member of the Sommelier Society, NJ
    - Speech for Les Amis Du Vin - Albany Chapter, March 1978
  - Speeches- Mark Miller (C) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Opening Remarks for panel participation at the Wine Media Guild, April 1985
    - Testimony of Miller before Special Senate Majority Committee on NY State Wine/Grape Industry, February 1984
    - Keynote Address to American Wine Society, Ohio, November 1984
    - La Fete du Muguet, May 1984
    - Knights of the Vine, November 1980
    - The Winemaker As Style Leader, November 1979
    - Home Winemaking Speech: Horticultural Heyday, 1979
    - A Rebirth of Premium Wine Growing in Hudson River Region
    - A Modern Investor's History of Eastern Viticulture
    - Variations of Vinification in Seyval Blanc- Fresh Spring Wines, Pennsylvania Conference
    - Viticulture in the Hudson Valley
    - Selection of Equipment for Small Winery, Annual Pennsylvania Wine Conference
  - Draft: For the Love of Wine
    Includes Story of Benmarl
    - Draft: For the Love of Wine (A), 1972,1982 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Draft: For the Love of Wine (B), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Draft: For the Love of Wine (C), 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Draft: For the Love of Wine (D) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Draft: For the Love of Wine (E), May 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Draft: For the Love of Wine (F), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Benmarl Wine Company Ltd, 1978,1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Includes Certificate of Incorporation, By Laws and Stock Offerings
    - Farm Winery License FW 1, November 4, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      This is the first Farm Winery License issued.
    - State of New York Legislative Resolution recognizing the accomplishments of Dene Grant Miller, March 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Also a letter to Miller from representative Richard E. Schermerhorn.
    - Pen used by Governor Hugh Carey to sign Assembly Bill 10135, an act to amend the alcoholic beverage control law, also known as the Farm Winery Act and associated document, June 4, 1976 (Box 4)
    - Photo of Governor Hugh Carey signing the Farm Winery Act, June 4, 1976 (Box 4)
- Series II. Photographs
  - Photos of Mark Miller (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photos removed from frames. Include Mark Miller, Eric Miller, Frank Prial, Marcia Mondavi, Dene Miller, Richard Barbour. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of vineyards (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Mark Miller at the vineyards (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Societe picnic (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of Benmarl Vineyards (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Includes photos of various events related to winemaking
  - Photographs for advertising (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Includes photos of models for advertising; Has negatives
- Series III. Magazines
  Magazines saved because most have an article about Benmarl, Mark Miller, or the Hudson Valley wine indusrty.
  - The Hudson Valley: Monthly Publication (2 copies), October 1972 (Box 2)
  - Datsun Discovery, September-October 1982 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, May 1978 (Box 2)
  - Wine now (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Vintage (2 copies), August-September 1976 (Box 2)
  - Country Living, December-January 1982 (3 copies) (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines (2 copies), June 1986 (Box 2)
  - The Hudson Valley, August 1987 (Box 2)
  - Datsun Discovery, September-October 1983 (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - Venture: The Magazine for Entrepreneurs (2 copies), August 1983 (Box 2)
  - Travel & Leisure: The Hudson River Valley (2 copies), July 1982 (Box 2)
  - The Hudson Valley, August 1984 (Box 2)
  - National Geographic, January 1978 (Box 2)
  - The Hudson Valley, May 1984 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, August 1986 (Box 2)
  - American Wine Society Journal, Fall 1984 (Box 2)
  - American Wine Society Journal, Spring 1984 (Box 2)
  - American Wine Society Journal, Summer 1984 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, March 1984 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, December 1983 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, February 1984 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, April 1985 (Box 2)
  - Appellation, March-April 1999 (Box 2)
  - The Hudson Valley, February 1993 (Box 2)
  - The Big Ability 5 (Box 2)
    Back cover has photograph of Miller
  - Money (2 copies), August 1977 (Box 2)
  - Eastern Grape Grower, February 1977 (Box 2)
  - Cuisine, July-August 1981 (Box 2)
  - Taste: Published Quarterly by the Culinary Institute of America, Winter 1985 (Box 2)
  - Signature (2 copies), May 1979 (Box 2)
  - Grape Grower, March 1985 (Box 2)
  - Cook's Magazine, July-August 1984 (Box 2)
  - Country Living, March 1985 (Box 2)
  - Wine East, January-February 1985 (Box 2)
  - Discovery, Fall 1985 (Box 2)
  - Time (2 copies), November 1977 (Box 2)
  - Avenue, November 1980 (Box 2)
  - Vogue, December 1980 (Box 2)
  - Eastern Grape Grower, February 1980 (Box 2)
  - Avenue, October 1979 (Box 2)
  - Wines & Vines, August 1972 (Box 2)
  - American Wine Society Journal, Winter 1985 (Box 2)
  - New York Alive, September/October 1983 (Box 2)
  - Smithsonian, January 2000 (Box 2)
  - Amvets, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Hudson Valley, June-July 1981 (Box 2)
  - Spotlight: A guide to the good life in the mid Hudson Valley, September 1972 (Box 2)
  - Avenue(3 copies), November 1980 (Box 2)
  - Highland Cultural Center (HCC) Arts: Celebrating a decade, 2004 (Box 2)
- Series IV. Newspaper Articles and other Publications
  - Lifestyles: Trying new wines adds to dining out fun (Barbara Ensrud), June 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - NYTimes, The Living Section: A Harvest of Upstate Wineries (2 copies) (Frank Frial), September 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Evening News:Marlboro Vintner's Wine Tops (2 Copies) (Tom Pray), October 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal, Farm News,: Valley Can Produce Best Wines, Miller says (Peter Eisner), June 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Art and Wine Bouquets (Walter Borawski), May 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lifestyles: Making wine at home a barrel of fun (Barbara Ensrud), November 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Sunday Freeman, Life,: New valley vintners on verge of success (Chazy Dowaliby), November 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Evening News, Hudson Valley Life: Love of fine wine led Mark Miller to Benmarl (4 copies) (Theresa Stynes), March 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Evening News, Family: Make That Jug of Wine Yourself (Audrey Morse), April 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal, Life & Leisure: He's Got Grape Expectations (Jim Detjen), January 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Sunday Freeman: Vintner Miller Feels Valley is Ready For A Wine Revival, July 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Herald News,Food: Stomp Over To Wineries (Jeanne Faust), July 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The NYTimes, RealEstate: Around Vineyards, It's Getting Crowded (3 copies) (Frank Prial), October 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Evening News: Hudson Valley Bubbles Again As Wine Producing Area, May 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal, Farm News: Ulster Winemaker Pushes 'Rural Renewal' in Valley (Mark Whittington), July 1976 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Taconic Press Newspapers: Dream of prestigious vineyard; Wringing a profit from the grape, (Ann Dauberman); Summer 1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Miscellanous Newspaper Article cuttings (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Articles (about Benmarl Vineyards and Mark Miller) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Articles (about Benmarl Vineyards) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of newspaper articles and journals about Benmarl Vineyards (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Articles Benmarl Vineyards from various sources (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Benmarl Wineletters (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles Times: Wine Country, USA, August 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes Wine Country: Vines Across Americe
  - ArtScience: Wine & Romance (Mary Koniz Arnold), Winter 1998/1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Independent: An October Day in New York Mahbub Husain Khan, November 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes a "Thank You " note from Mark Miller
  - Los Angeles Times: New York's Finest (2 copies) (Dan Berger), August 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: The winemaker's art (3 copies), May 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - News(Southeast Orange and Northeast Orange): Artists of the Area Featuring Mark Miller, July/August 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Enjoy, Poughkeepsie Journal: Advertise on Mark Miller's Paintings Exhibition, September 2002 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pioneer: Miller offering several illustrations, January 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pioneer: Library Art show, August 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Journal News, The Weekend Traveler: Sippiing the Hudson Valley's Autumn Beauty, November 1999 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Pioneer: Benmarl is getting a record number of fall tourists, October 2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Evening News: Continuously Operated Benmarl Vineyards oldest in country (Ruth Valenti), June 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The New York Times: Raising the Stakes for New York Wine (2 copies) (Frank Prial), December 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Evening News: Renowned Winemaker's secret :mix hobby, enterprise(3 copies), June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Benmarl winery, January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes photo of Miller
  - The Evening News: Marlboro artist specializes in romantic scenes (3 copies) (Story by Rebecca Neale and Photos by Tim Reese), December 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes illustrations of Miller's work
  - The New York Times: Owning a small piece of Hudson Valley vineyard, October 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Evening News, Hudson Valley Life: Love of fine wine led Mark Miller to Benmarl (Donna Schwartz), March 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sunday Magazine: A sparkling account of winemaking (3 copies) (Beth Mullally), April 1984 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Review of Miller's book "Wine- A Gentleman's Game"
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Winter's work, February 1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes photo of pruning grape wines at Benmarl
  - The New York Times: Wine Talk (Frank Prial), October 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Hudson Valley Newspapers: County Legislators visit Benmarl Winery, June 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sunday Record: Eastern Winemakers raising their glasses, October 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Includes photo of Miller in wine cellar at Benmarl winery
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Thanks to all those who have joined in discovering wine (John Given), May 1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Winery wards off winter in Groundhog Day party, February 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Daily Freeman: Marlboro winemaker harvests praise for vintage Nixon portrait (2 copies), March 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sunday Freeman, Business: Preservation Illustrated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes an article about Miller selling Benmarl Vineyards to Fordham University in 1993 while still preserving the scenic land
  - Daily Freeman, Life: Wine, woman and song (2 copies), January 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Miller illustrates cover for popular singer Lisa Loeb
  - The Times Herald-Record: From 'Kitten' to 'Firecracker' (3 copies) (Caitlin Ingrassia), January 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Miller's digital modification for Lisa Loeb's album cover
  - Lifestyle: Cooking with Hudson Valley Wines (3 copies), September 1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Article on Miller in The Korea Times, New York, July 1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Herald Tribune: Festival With Wine, September 1958 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Enjoy: Art from all sorts of angles (Florence Pennella) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes artwork to be displayed in Benmarl Vineyards
  - The Evening News: Benmarl Winery Harvest Festival set for Saturday (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sunday: Vintage Miller (2 copies), May 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Include articles on Miller, his art and Benmarl Vineyards (Stories by Lou Hansen and Photos by Eric Krieger)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal, Life: Vintage Portrait, December 1992 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Article on Miller's portrait of Nixon
  - Wineries feature premiere vintages, May 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Times Herald Record: Benmarl on sale block (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Article on sale of vineyard for $2.75 M pricetag
  - The Wall Street Journal: Winemaker Fosters Vintage Art Forms (Tessa DeCarlo), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Attached a memo addressed to Miller
  - Almanac: The way we were, July 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Article on Miller's art of the 1950s
  - Daily Freeman, Getting around: Wineries host adventurers searching for perfect grape (Philip Farber), August 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Times Herald Record: Drought could make 1999 a flavorful year for wine (Letitia Campbell) (2 copies), August 1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Art Times: Painting with an Electronic Brush (Mark Miller), September 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sunday Record: Prize portrait (2 copies), March 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Article on Miller's portrait of Nixon making it to the Nixon Library
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Drink up- winter is here for a while (Bond Brungard), February 2003 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Marlboro vineyard toasts groundhog
  - The Evening News, Entertainment: Photo of Miller diaplaying his work at Benmarl, June 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Times Herald Record, Sunday Features: Fine Vines (Caitlin Ingrassia), November 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Times Herald Record: Vineyards wine and dine visitors, September 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sunday News: No sour grapes here, October 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Includes photos of Benmarl Vineyards
  - Business: Benmarl still pioneering in winemaking (Jonathan Ment), December 2001 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Daily Freeman, Life: Illustraing an era, March 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Marlboro museum to preserve images from magazine heyday
  - Micro Publishing News: PhotoCD, June 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Advertising Age: Articles on Wine Marketing (4 copies), January 1983 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Don Quixote on the Hudson: Benmarl's Mark Miller Dreams Big (Story by Matthew Debord and Photos by Sara Matthews), October 2001 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - No sour grapes here: Harvesting of vineyard calls for a party, October 1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes various photos of Miller and others at Benmarl
  - Internationally Known Painter, Sculptor Turns Energies To Art Of Winemaking (Story by Gigi Gillett and Photos by Ev Landers), September 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Th e New York Times: Ulster Vintner's Harvest Brings Out a Host of Helpers, September 1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Some newspaper articles on Miller and his early life (Includes pictures) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Wine making At Home in Marlboro (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Sunday Freeman: Marlboro's Vineyards - An Old World Flavor (Wine Lover's Society Formed), February 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Sunday Freeman: Our Hudson Wines - Far From Foxy (Tobie Geertsema Tempo), March 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes photo of Miller with Hamilton Mowbray, Warren Smith, Jan Jensen, Eric Miller
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Art and Wine Bouquets (2 copies) (Walter Borawski), May 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mid-Hudson Business Journal: Mark Miller's Benmarl Vineyards Started as Hobby, Now produces Wine For a Select Clientele (R L Jones), October 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sunday Record: Hudson Vintner hopes to rival French masters (Story and photos by Everett Landers), October 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes photos of Miller and his sons examining vineyards
  - The Daily Freeman: Vineyard in Marlboro seeks grape growers (By Jon Powers), July 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Includes photos of Miller and his son tending grape harvest
  - The Benmarl Vineyards Vigneron, Spring 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Article on " Mark Miller:'For Love Of Wine' " (Anton Gross) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Village Voice: "West Bank Wines: The Hudson River Region", September 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - How Spoiled Can One Be! (Harry Waugh), September 1974 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Includes experiences of tasting various wines from Benmarl Vineyards
  - The New York Times: New Yorkers Can Take Pride in Their Thriving, Surprising Hudson Valley Wines (6 copies), November 1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Grape Grower: Benmarl Vineyards, Developing the hillsides in the Hudson Valley of New York, February 1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hudson Valley Grape-Wine Conference Held (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Faces in Wine: Mark Miller (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Hampton Estate Vineyards: Limited Partnership (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Also Includes "Benmarl Vineyards Story: Fascinating history and outstanding wines"
  - Sunday Journal News: Days of wine..Grape harvest in the Hudson Highlands (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vieux Cru (Mark Miller) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Our Town: On Wines (Jonathan Levine) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New York Times: A Harvest Sampler of Wineries in New York State (16 copies) (Frank Prial) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - From the Vine: Truth in vineyards (Judy Peterson-Nedry) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Times Herald Record: Interest in wine coolers bubbling, September 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Essex Journal: Putting your reading where your mouth is (Alan Caruba) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New York Times: In time for summer, two guides to New York wineries, June 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - New York Hudson Valley: Visiting the Vineyards (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Something Foxy: Of Vignerons and Kissing Scenes (Foxy Gwynne) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - The Beverage Communicator: The Grape Vine, Benmarl Vineyards promotes wine art (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - There's a fine wine in Marlboro country (2 copies) (Anthony Dias Blue) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Sunday Freeman: 'Waiter..A Good Local Wine, Please' (2 copies), March 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - From the Stockpot: Benmarl Winery (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Farm News: Valley can Produce Best (Peter Eisner) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Southern Ulster Pioneer: Farm Winery Bill Signed, June 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Grape growers, wine makers gather to boost local brew (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Benmarl winery on air, November 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Flowing Bowl ..in the Hudson Valley (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Poughkeepsie Journal: Local wine sellers find "A Thirsty Market", November 1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Wine Lines: "Burgundy on the Hudson: Benmarl" (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Evening News: Marlboro Vintner's Wine Tops (Tom Pray), October 1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Includes photo of Miller examining his vineyard
  - Vineyards Promise Valley Prosperity (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Los Angekes Times: New york's Finest (Dan Berger), August 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New York Sunday News: New York wine comes of age, October 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Testing the fruit of Hudson Valley vines (Sylvia Fine) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Marlborough Record: Wine festival attracts 200 at Mark Miller Farm, September 1961 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - New York Times: "Wine Talk: An estate bottled California brand is sold only by mail order and parcel delivery" (Frank Prial), August 1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Sunday Freeman: Marlboro's vineyards - an old world flavor, February 1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)